American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIa. 1743-1806 APS.Archives.IIa APS.Archives.IIa
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Report of the committee on Couldery's lamp, July 21, 1797; 7 1/2" x 9 1/16"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: R[obert] Patterson, C[harles] W[illson] Peale. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 261.
  - Report of the committee appointed to make an analysis of the third piece on education, July 23, 1797; 7 13/16" x 9 15/16"; American Philosophical Society
    submitted for the premium, Philadelphia, 13 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: Moreau de St. Mery, Ja[me]s Abercrombie, Jona[than] Williams.
  - Edward Williams to the President of the College at Philadelphia, August 2, 1797; 8" x 9 5/8"; Williams, Edward
    Drawing Room, Tower, London, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. By order of Marquis Cornwallis transmits "a Copy of the Account of the Trigonometrical Survey carried on in this Country
  - Jasper Moylan to John Vaughan, August 9, 1797; 7 7/8" x 11"; Moylan, Jasper
    Treasurer of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Executors of the late Benjamin Franklin demand Payment of £500 bond to his testator (Richard bache) "in the course of the present month."
  - Letter to Messrs. Rich. p. and Sam. H. Smith, Aug. 18, 1797; 7 1/2" x 9 1/4"; Ebeling, Christophe Daniel, 1741-1817
    Hamburgh, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Acknowledges Eulogium of Mr. Rittenhouse sent by the Philosophical society.
  - Report of committee on [John Redmond] Coxe's paper on opium, Nov. 24, 1797; 5x7-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Adam Seybert. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.263. Printed: Trans., o.s., vol. IV, 387 ff.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred a paper on Indian music, December 1, 1797; 6 1/4" x 7 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: G[eorge] Turner, R[obert] Patterson. See Pro., X1II, pt. 3, 263, 264.
  - The Insurance Company of North America to John Vaughan, December 2, 1797; 4 1/2" x 7 3/8"; Insurance Company of North America
    Treasurer of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: John Cook. Duplicate. Receipt for $15.60, for renewal of $4,000 insurance on Philosophical Hall and $1,200 on library and apparatus.
  - Report of the committee appointed to reinsure the building, CR-1, December 15, 1797; 8" x 9"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: J[oh]n Vaughan, R[obert] Patterson. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 265.
  - Report of the committee appointed to examine the treasurer's accounts, December 15, 1797; 8" x 9 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: R[obert] Patterson. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 264-265.
  - Report of committee upon the delivery of paper on education to Alexander Moore, December 16, 1797; 7 15/16" x 9 15/16"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsements. A.D.S.: Jona[thann] Williams. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 266.
  - Concerning the prevention of decay in peach trees, Dec. 15, 1797; 13x8; Lime, pseud.
    [read] D. 2p.and add.,end. (see Ms. comm.to the APS. Natural history, vol. 1, no. 19.) Entered for the premium. Cf. Minutes, pp.264, 269, 303. On same sheet is: APS Report of committee...; Oct. 2, 1800.
  - Concerning the prevention of decay in peach trees, Dec. 26, 1797; 8-1/2x7; X, pseud.
    D. 12p.,end. (see MS.comm. to the APS. Natural history,vol.1,no.20.) Entered for the premium. Cf. Minutes, p.269. On same sheet is: APS Report of committee;Oct. 2, 1800.
  - Article on premature death of peach trees, Dec., 1797; 13x8; Coulter, Thomas
    A.D. 2p. and end. (see Ms. Comm. to APS. Natural history, vol. 1, no.19) Enclosed originally with letter from Coulton to T.Jefferson; Dec. 4, 1797.
  - Letter to ----, 1797; 13x8; Latrobe, Benjamin Henry, 1764-1820
    A.L.S. 14p.and end. (see Ms. Comm.to the APS. Mechanics, Machinery, Eng., etc., no. 18.) Architectural acoustics.
  - Alex[ander] Martin to Jonathan Williams, January 1, 1798; 7 7/8" x 9 1/2"; Martin, Alexander, 1740-1807
    ----, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Letter acknowledging election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Report of the committee appointed to draft an introduction to the two essays on education to which premiums were adjudged, January 19, 1798; 7 15/16" x 9 13/16"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: G[eorge] Turner, R[obert] Patterson, Jona[than] Williams.
  - Summary of relations of American Philosophical Society with the college of Physicians, February 16, November 4, 1798, 1814; 10 1/8" x 16 3/8"; American Philosophical Society
    2 pp. and endorsement. D. Unsigned.
  - The American Philosophical Society to Samuel Lewis, March 2, 1798; 8" x 10 1/4"; American Philosophical Society
    [Dr.], Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. D.S.: Sam[uel] H. Smith, Th[omas] Jefferson; receipted by Samuel Lewis. Bill for $5.24 for filling up diplomas for A.P.S.
  - Report of the committee appointed, March 2, 1798; 10 3/4" x 17"; American Philosophical Society
    on offering a premium for essays on education, [Philadelphia], March 2, 1798. 3 pp. and endorsements. Dr.D.
  - Report of the committee appointed to confer with a committee of the College of Physicians relative to the rent of the room, March 16, 1798; 8" x 9 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 2 pp. and endorsement. Dr.D. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 268-269.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred the communication on ship pumps signed "Improvement", March 16, 1798; 7 15/16" x 9 15/16"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 2 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: Jona[than] Williams, C[harles] W[illson] Peale. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 269.
  - B[enjamin] S[mith] Barton to Samuel H. Smith, March 16, 1798; 8" x 13 1/4"; Barton, Benjamin Smith, 1766-1815
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Requests additional time in which to prepare discourse to be delivered before the A.P.S.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., March 30, 1798; 10x7-1/2; Smith, Samuel Harrison, 1772-1845
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. (see Ms.comm.to the APS. Philology, literature, etc., vol. 1, no. 10.) Donates his award for future awards.
  - Committee of the A.P.S. to committee of the College of Physicians, April 6, 1798; 8 7/8" x 14 1/4"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 2 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: T. B. Smith, J[oh]n Vaughan, for A.P.S.; ----, Thomas Parke, for College of Physicians. Terms of lease.
  - Report of committee appointed to enquire into the state of the catalogue..., April 6, 1798; 7 3/4" x 8 1/4"; American Philosophical Society
    A.D.S: Sam. H. Smith 1p. and end. See Minutes, April 6, 1798; also Library bulletion, 1943,pp.76-82.
  - Resolution authorizing president to sign such contract or mortgage as may be entered into to relieve mortgage to Dr. Franklin for £500, April 20, 1798; 6-1/4x7-3/4; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D.S.: Th. Jefferson, Presidt. 1p.and end.
  - John Ormrod to Jonathan Williams, May 8, 1798; 6" x 7 1/4"; Ormrod, John, b. ca. 1770
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. A.D.S. Receipt for $6.25, for paper and printing of three hundred circular letters for the A.P.S.
  - Report of the committee upon a paper on the preservation of peach trees, May 18, 1798; 7 3/4" x 12 1/2"; American Philosophical Society
    submitted for the premium by "A.B.G.", [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: William Bache, C[harles] W[illson] Peale. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 271.
  - Report of the Secretary relative to the publication of A.P.S. Transactions, IV., June 1, 1798; 8" x 12 9/16"; American Philosophical Society
    IV. [Philadelphia], 3 pp. and endorsements. A.D.S.: Sam[uel] H. Smith. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 271. Mentions article by Thomas Jefferson.
  - Experiments and conjectures on magnetism & electricity., June 11, 1798; 7 1/4" x 8 3/4"; Williams, Jonathan, 1750-1815
    Mount Pleasant, A.D.S. 17p. and end. (The first portion of this paper was written in Paris in 1784) This paper was read before the American philosophical society, June 15,1798; cf. Minutes of that date.
  - R[obert] Patterson to Samuel Magaw, June 12, 1798; 4 1/2" x 7 1/4"; Patterson, Robert, 1743-1824
    Philadelphia, 2pp. and endorsements. D.S.: R[obert] Patterson. Promissory note for $1,200 to be paid to order of Samuel Magaw sixty days after date.
  - The American Philosophical Society to Edward Duffield and Henry Hill, June 19, 1798; 7 3/4" x 12 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    executors of Benjamin Franklin, [Dr.], Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsements. D.S.: Jon[atha]n Penrose, Sh[eri]ff. Receipted bill for $1,472.67 paid in full of bond due to Benjamin Franklin. FILM 54-61 FRAME 118
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred a communication of Dr. [Nicholas] Collin, June 22, 1798; 7 9/16" x 9 13/16"; American Philosophical Society
    on the comparison of kindred words of the languages of different nations, Philadelphia, 6 pp. and endorsements. Dr.D.S.: Peter S. DuPonmeau, B[enjamin] S[mith] Barton, J[oh]n Vaughan. See Pro., XXII, pt. 273.
  - Plan and description of a horizontal wheel, invented by Samuel Felsted, July 6, 1798; 8" x 13"; Felsted, Samuel, 1743-1802
    Kingston, Jamaica, A.D.S. [3]8p. 3p1. Paper board binding. Presented to the Society by the author, Aug. 16, 1799.
  - A[nthony] Fothergill to the [American] Philosophical Society, August 12, 1798; 7 1/4" x 9 1/8"; Fothergill, A. (Anthony), 1732?-1813
    Bath, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents to A.P.S.: (1) Appendix to his Inquiry on the Suspension of Vital Action; (2) New Premium book of Bath Agricultural Society.
  - Samuel Hodgdon to Jonathan Williams, October 10, 1798; 7 7/8" x 9 3/4"; Hodgdon, Samuel, 1745-1824
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. Concerning three barrels [of bones] sent from the west to the A.P.S. Fever in Philadelphia.
  - Report of Adam Seybert to [the American Philosophical Society], November 22, 1798; 6 3/8" x 7 15/16"; Seybert, Adam, 1773-1825
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.D.S. Recommends publication of Thomas Smith's paper on a vessel for boiling inflammable fluids. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 273.
  - Jon[athan] Williams to John Vaughan, October 13, 1798; 5 1/2" x 7 7/8"; Williams, Jonathan, 1750-1815
    Treasurer of A.P.S., ----, 2 pp. A.D.S. Order to pay to Samuel Hodgdon $22.50 for transporting three barrels of bones from the west to the A.P.S.
  - R[obert] Patterson to Peter S. DuPonceau, October 16, 1798; 3 1/4" x 8"; Patterson, Robert, 1743-1824
    Philadelphia, 2pp. and endorsements. D.S.: R[obert] Patterson. Promissory note for $1,100 to be paid to Peter S. DuPonceau or order sixty days after date.
  - Report of Sam[uel] H. Smith to [the American Philosophical Society,], October 28, 1798; 7" x 7 3/4"; Smith, Samuel Harrison, 1772-1845
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsements. A.D.S. Reports as worthy of publication [Benjamin Henry] Latrobe's paper on the sandhills of Cape Henry.
  - J[oh]n Vaughan to the President of the American Philosophical Society, November 23, 1798; 8 1/8" x 9 5/8"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsements. A.L.S. William Jones presents to the A.P.S.: George Adams, Microscopes, 2d. ed. with volume of plates; George Adams, Graphical Essays, with volume of plates. See
  - The American Philosophical Society to Jona[than] Williams, November 24, 1798; 8 1/8" x 13 3/8"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Jona[than] Williams; Adam Seybert. Receipted bill for $28.81 for expenses of A.P.S. paid by Jonathan Williams.
  - Report of the permanent committee... on natural history, November 24, 1798; 7 13/16" x 9 3/4; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 4 pp. and endorsements. D.S.: Jon[athan] Williams. Report upon objects of natural history submitted to the Society. Printed in full in Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 274-275.
  - Report of the committee upon Dr. Sehultz's memoir on noxious plants, December 7, 1798; 6 5/8" x 8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 3 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: Benjamin Smith Barton, Adam Seybert. Do not recommend publication of paper. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 275.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred Dr. [Joseph] Priestley's dissertation on phlogiston, [Philadelphia], December 7, 1798; 6 3/4" x 7 5/8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Adam Seybert, James Woodhouse. Report that the paper has been placed in the hands of the printer.
  - Report of the committee to whom were referred the papers of [Adam] Seybert and [James] Woodhouse on the supposed wall in the state of North Carolina, December 21, 1798; 7 7/8" x 9 15/16"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 2 pp. and endorsements. A.D.S.: C[aspar] Wistar, Jr. Recommend that the two papers submitted be combined.
  - [List of papers and communications submitted to the American Philosophical Society,], December 27, 1798; 7 15/16" x 9 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 7 pp. and endorsement. D. Covers the period from January 27, 1797 to December 27, 1798. Mentions articles by T.Jefferson.
  - R[obert] Patterson to John Vaughan, December 29, 1798; 4 3/8" x 7 7/8"; Patterson, Robert, 1743-1824
    Treasurer of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: R[obert] Patterson. Receipt for $12.03, received of John Vaughan for discount on $1,100 note lent the Society on October 16, 1798.
  - Report on the catalogue accompanying the presentation of the same, Decembr 13, 1799; 6 3/4" x 8 1/4"; American Philosophical Society
    by the committee appointed to form it, Read & accepted D. 4p. Written by Nicholas Collin; see Minutes, Dec. 13, 1799;also Library bulletin,1943 pp.76-82.
  - List of officers, Oct., 1799; 9-1/2x8; Connecticut Academy of Arts and Sciences
    A.D.S.: S. Baldwin. 1p.and end. (see Ms.comm.to the APS. Philology, literature, etc., vol. 1, no. 11c.) Cf. Minutes, p.290. Enclosed originally in letter from the Conn.Academy to A.Seybert; Dec.25,1799.
  - The Insurance Company of North America to John Vaughan, January 4, 1799; 4 1/2" x 8 1/4"; Insurance Company of North America
    Treasurer of A.P.S., [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: Cha[rle]s P. Heath. Receipt for $15.60, for renewal of $4,000 insurance on Philosophical Hall and $1,200 on books.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred [Benjamin Smith] Barton's communication on the fatal effects of Equisetum hyemale when eaten by horses, January 7, 1799; 7 7/8" x 9 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: J[onathan] Williams, Adam Seybert. Recommended for publication. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 276, 278.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred the memoir of Dr. [James] Woodhouse on phlogiston, January 18, 1799; 7 1/8" x 8 15/16"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: C[aspar] Wistar, jr., Adam Seybert. Publication recommended. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 278.
  - J[oh]n Vaughan, Treasurer of A.P.S., January 20, 1799; 7 1/2" x 8 3/4"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    to J[ohn] B. Guenat, [Philadelphia], 3 pp., address and endorsement. A.D.S. Order to John B. Guenat to collect dues in arrears from members listed herein., among whom is T.Jefferson.
  - J[onathan] Williams to the President of the [America] Philosophical Society, January 24, 1799; 7 7/8" x 9 11/16"; Williams, Jonathan, 1750-1815
    Mount Pleasant, 2 pp., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Declining to act on the permanent committee for collecting information relative to the natural history of the U. S.
  - Report of Sam[uel] H. Smith to [the American Philosophical Society,], February 1, 1799; 6 1/2" x 7 7/8"; Smith, Samuel Harrison, 1772-1845
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.D.S. Reports as worthy of publication, Dr. Barton's communication supplementary to Mr. Latrobe's paper on the sandhills of Virginia.
  - Report of the committee appointed to consider the propriety of offering a premium for the best essay on the subject of education, February 15, 1799; 7 1/4" x 9"; American Philosophical Society
    and the terms upon which it should be offered, [Philadelphia,] 3 pp. and endorsement. D.
  - R[obert] Patterson to John Vaughan, February 18, 1799; 4 1/8" x 6 3/4"; Patterson, Robert, 1743-1824
    Treasurer of A.P.S., [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. A.D.S. Receipt for $134.79 received of John Vaughan and C. W. Peale toward payment of $900 note due at Bank of the U. S.
  - John B. Guenat to John Vaughan, February 28, 1799; 3 7/8" x 6 1/4"; Guenat, John B.
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. A.D.S. Receipt for $7.10, being commission for recovering $142 in subscriptions due to the A.P.S.
  - Report of committee on H[ugh] Williamson's paper on Ephoron leucon, March 1, 1799; 5x6-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: Benjamin S. Barton and C.W.Peale. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.280. Printed: Trans.,o.s.,vol.V, 71ff.
  - Report of the committee to whom were referred the memoirs from the several candidates for the premium offered for the best essay on warming rooms, March 15, 1799; 7 3/4" x 13"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: R[obert] Patterson, C[aspar] Wistar, jr. Suggest award to author of piece signed "Oeconomy."
  - Report [of William Shippen, Jr.] to the Presi[dent of the American philosophical society, March 15, 1799; 8x10; Shippen, William, 1736?-1808
    Philadelphia], A.D.S. 1p. and end. Add. torn. Recommends publication of Dr. Wistar's description of the bones of an unknown animal. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 280.
  - J[oh]n Vaughan to Sam[ue]l H. Smith, March 18, 1799; 7 1/2" x 9"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Fi Secretary of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Relative to money for Michaux left in hands of David Rittenhouse. Requests that receipts of Dr. Rittenhouse be delivered up.
  - Charts pertaining to the eclipse of the moon, 1799 April 6-May 2-4; 18" x 13"; Lambert, William
    and of the sun, June 16 1806, for the meridian of Philadelphia. Philadelphia, April 6, May 2, May 14,1799. 3 D. ca. Presented to Thomas Jefferson, President, and to the other officers and members of the A.P.S..." Cf. Minutes, May 17,1799.
  - R[obert] Patterson to John Vaughan, April 15, 1799; 5" x 8 1/4"; Patterson, Robert, 1743-1824
    [Philadelphia], 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Concerning note for $900, and possibility of reducing same to $600 or $650 on April 23.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred R. R. Livingston's paper on steam engines, April 19, 1799; 8" x 9 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: R[obert] Patterson, C[harles] W[illson] Peale. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 281.
  - B[enjamin] Henry Latrobe to [Robert Patterson], April 19, 1799; 7 7/8" x 12 3/4"; Latrobe, Benjamin Henry, 1764-1820
    Philadelphia, 7 pp. and endorsements. A.L.S. Opinion on Robert R. Livingston's memoir on steam engines.
  - Report of James Woodhouse to [the American Philosophical Society, Philadelphia], May 3, 1799; 7 15/16" x 9 13/16"; Woodhouse, James
    1 p. and endorsement. A.D.S. Refuses to recommend for publication the paper by Henry Wynkoop on mitigating yellow fever. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 280, 280.
  - W[illia]m Jones to the American Philosophical Academy (sic), May 26, 1799; 6 1/4" x 7 3/4"; Jones, William, 1763-1831
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. 3d. per. L. Presents Works of [George] Adams, edited by himself.
  - R[obert] Patterson to John Vaughan, June 6, 1799; 3" x 8"; Patterson, Robert, 1743-1824
    Treasurer of A.P.S., [Philadelphia], 1 p. A.D.S. Receipt for $89.28, received of John Vaughan toward note due at Bank of the U. S., thus reducing debt to $600.
  - W[illia]m Jones to John Vaughan, June 24, 1799; 7 1/2" x 9 1/8"; Jones, William, 1763-1831
    London, 2 pp. A.L.S. Donates pair of globes to the A.P.S.
  - Receipt to John Vaughan for a book, July 25, 1799; 3x7-1/4; Ogilby, Joseph
    Philadelphia, A.D.S. 1p. (This was found in 476:Sm3 (July 1961).
  - R[obert] Patterson to John Vaughan, August 13, 1799; 5 3/4" x 7 3/4"; Patterson, Robert, 1743-1824
    Treasurer of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.D.S. Receipted by C. W. Peale. Note authorizing payment of $60 to C.W. Peale and Raphael Peale for prize essay on warming rooms.
  - D[avi]d Nassy to the Philosophical society of Philadelphia (sic), August 18, 1799; 8" x 12 1/2"; Nassy, David de Isaac Cohen, 1747-1806
    Surinam, 3 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. (In French.) Donates his Lettre sur les juifs to the A.P.S. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 285, November 15, 1799.
  - R[obert] Patterson to John Vaughan, August 21, 1799; 4" x 9"; Patterson, Robert, 1743-1824
    Treasurer of A.P.S., [Philadelphia], 1p. and endorsement. D.S. Receipt for $105.43, received of John Vaughan and C. W. Peale toward note due at Bank of the U. S., thus reducing debt to $500.
  - W(illia)m D. Peck to B(enjamin) S(mith) Barton, September 20, 1799; 7 3/4" x 9 7/8"; Peck, William Dandridge, 1763-1822
    Kittery, 2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges election to membership in A.P.S. Discussion upon natural history.
  - R[obert] Patterson to J[oh]n Vaughan, October 29, 1799; 4 5/8" x 8 1/4"; Patterson, Robert, 1743-1824
    Treasurer of A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. D.S. Receipt for $104.37, received of John Vaughan toward note due at Bank of the U. S., thus reducing debt to $400.
  - Report of committee on [David] Hosack's paper on tetanus, Nov. 6, 1799; 5x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: James Woodhouse and Adam Seybert. 1p.and end. Cf. Minutes, p.285.
  - Report of secretaries relative to deficient plates in A.P.S. Transactions, IV., November 6, 1799; 8" x 12 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    IV. [Philadelphia], 2 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: Adam Seybert, Sam[uel] H. Smith, James Woodhouse. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 284. Mentions Thomas Jefferson.
  - C[harles] W[illson] Peale to the members of the American Philosophical Society, November 6, 1799; 6 3/8" x 7 7/8"; Peale, Charles Willson, 1741-1827
    Museum, [Philadelphia], 1 p. A.N. in 3d. per. Invitation to attend introductory lecture to a course on natural history, to be delivered at the University of Pennsylvania. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 284-285.
  - List of apparatus belonging to the..., December 6, 1799; 7 1/2" x 9 13/16"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: R[obert] Patterson, Joseph Clay, Tho[ma]s P. Smith. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 286.
  - Report of the committee appointed to call on Thomas Dobson, December 6, 1799; 6 3/8" x 7 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    the printer, [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. A.D.S.: G[eorge] Turner. With reference to completing A.P.S. Transactions, IV. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 286.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred the description of an horizontal windmill, December 6, 1799; 7 7/8" x 8"; American Philosophical Society
    invented by John Felstead, Kingston in Jamaica, [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: R[obert] Patterson, B[enjamin] H[enry] Latrobe. Publication not recommended. Publication not recommended.
  - Report of the committee to whom was referred the report of a committee appointed to revise the bye-laws of the Society, December 6, 1799; 7 3/8" x 7 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 287.
  - Resolution appointing a committee to receive the legacy bequeathed by Mrs. Hannah Rittenhouse, December 6, 1799; 7 9/16" x 8 7/8"; American Philosophical Society